Natonek, Hans; Papers ger004
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hans Natonek Papers1918-1964
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Natonek, Hans, 1892-1963
ger004
3.25 cubic ft.
Natonek worked as a newspaper editor in his native Prague and in Leipzig before fleeing to France in 1939 and to the United States in 1941. His autobiography, In Search of Myself, was published in New York in 1943. The bulk of Natonek's manuscripts date from his later career in Tucson, Arizona, from where he wrote for American and European newspapers and magazines.
Biographical Sketch
Born of German-Jewish ancestry in Prague on Oct. 25, 1892, Hanus (Hans) Natonek grew up in the Austro-Hungarian Empire. After completion of his university studies in Prague, Vienna and Berlin, Natonek became chief editor of the Neue Leipziger Zeitung in 1917, a post he held until 1933. The author of many novels and short stories, Natonek attained official recognition in 1932 when he received the prestigious Goethe Award from the city of Leipzig for his novel Kinder Einer Stadt. In addition, Natonek was a theater critic and contributor to many magazines and journals.
His marriage to Gertrud Huther in 1918, producing two children, a son Wolfgang born in 1919 and a daughter Susanne born in 1924, ended in divorce.
With the advent of the Nazi Regime in 1933, Natonek fled Germany and returned to Prague. There he continued his advocacy of a democratic press. In 1938 he was divorced from his second wife, Erica Clara Wassermann. After Czechoslovakia collapsed in 1938, Natonek was compelled to emigrate to France, spending the next few years hiding from the Nazis. He "slept on docks, under trucks and in the cold fog of the Pyrenees Mountains" [New York Times, 63: O 25; 32: 1]. In 1941, aided by the Emergency Rescue Committee and the President's Advisory Committee, he reached New York City.
Natonek's first two years in America were very difficult. He supported himself by doing menial odd jobs while writing of his experiences in Suche Nach Mir Selbst (In Search of Myself). In 1943 he moved to Tuscon, Arizona, where he continued his literary pursuits, contributing stories and poems to newspapers and magazines in the United States and in Europe. In 1949 he married Anne Morgenstern Grunwald, a native of Frankfurt, Germany, who lived with him until his death from leukemia on Oct. 24, 1963.
Scope and Contents
The Hans Natonek Papers are of interest to researchers in German exile literature, Judaic studies, the novel and the short story, and to researchers in the field of European history. Important themes in his works are the Jewish identity, the individual in society, journalism in Germany and freedom of expression. Also of interest are the attempts of a prominent ĂmigrĂŠ author to establish a writing career in an new language and culture.
Natonek's association with other notable figures of the period, such as Joseph Roth, Leonhard Frank, Erich Kastner, Franz Werfel, Alma Mahler-Werfel, Thomas, Golo and Heinrich Mann, Walter Mehring, Hertha Pauli and Ernst Weiss, make him an interesting subject for research. The papers contain correspondence with Kastner but, unfortunately, none with his other colleagues. The letter from Erich Kastner on behalf of Natonek's incarcerated son and Natonek's letter to Theodor Heuss are especially noteworthy. Joseph Roth was a special friend of Natonek and is the subject of several articles and stories in this collection.
The papers contain, for the most part, drafts of Natonek's novels, short stories and poems, as well as his correspondence with family and publishers. The bulk of the literary works in this collection, though undated, stem from the period after he fled to the United States, mainly after he moved to Arizona in 1943.
Arrangement of the Collection
Divided into 3 topic file series
Acquisition Information
All items in the Hans Natonek Papers were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Mrs. Anne G. Natonek on 17 March 1981.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Authors.; Poems..; Correspondence.; Novels.; Diaries.; Literature
- Autobiographical and Biographical Material, 1892-1963; 1; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains diaries and memoirs, passport, certificates, curriculum vitae, photographs, newspaper clippings (biographical and obituaries).
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Activities in Arizona, ca. 1944 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 1)
  - Diary Fragment, ca. 1944 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 2)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 1-150, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 3)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 151-299, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 4)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 300-441, Undated (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 5)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 1-150, Undated; copy (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 6)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 151-299, Undated; copy (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 7)
  - Memoirs and Diaries, pp. 300-441, Undated; copy (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 8)
  - Obituaries, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 9)
  - Passport, Certificates, Photographs, Curriculum Vitae, 1892-1963 (Box 1 (1-Autobiographical and Biographical Material), Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1940-1963; 2; 0.25 cubic ft.
  Contains correspondence with publishers relating to the author's struggles to find an american market for his works. Also contains correspondence relating to his escape from Europe in 1940 and to his campaign to free his son from East Germany during the 1950s. The correspondence is primarily with family members, especially with his son, Wolfgang Natonek.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 1 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
- Literary Works, 1924-1925; 1933-1949; 1958-1963; 3; 2.5 cubic ft.
  Contains hand corrected typescripts and carbon copies of articles, essays, novels, poems, and short stories.
  Arranged alphabetically in five subseries: Novels; Poems; Short Stories, Essays and Articles; Fragments; Miscellaneous Published Articles and Poems.
  - Novels, 1925; 1941-1945; 1947; 1963; 3.1
    - Blaubart, Marshall von Frankreich, ca. 1941 (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 14)
    - Bluebeard, Marshall of France, ca. 1943 (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 15)
    - Destination Unknown, pp. 1-140, ca. 1945 (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 16)
    - Destination Unknown, pp. 141-281, Undated (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 17)
    - Footprints in the Desert, ca. 1943 (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 18)
    - Fraulein Thea (with Charles G. Finney), 1945 (Box 1 (3-Literary Works), Folder 19)
    - Geld Regiert Die Welt oder Die Abenteuer Des Gewissens, 1930 (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 1)
    - Give Me Joy, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 2)
    - Kampf um die Glaskugel, pp. 1-152, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 3)
    - Kampf um die Glaskugel, pp. 153-301, Undated; carbon (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 4)
    - Kampf um die Glaskugel, pp. 1-152, Undated; carbon (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 5)
    - Kampf um die Glaskugel, pp. 153-301, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 6)
    - Legacy of Lazarus, ca. 1963 (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 7)
    - Legacy of Lazarus, ca. 1963; copy (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 8)
    - Lilith (with Charles G. Finney), Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 9-10)
    - The Revolt of the Trained Seals (with Mildred Clingerman), ca. 1947 (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 11)
    - Die Strabe Des Verrats, ca. 1925 (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 12)
    - Thomas and Theresa, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 13)
    - Untitled Fragment, 1. Fassung, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 14)
    - Yesterday is Tomorrow, pp. 1-177, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 15)
    - Yesterday is Tomorrow, pp. 178-391, Undated (Box 2 (3-Literary Works), Folder 16)
  - Poems, 1933-1935; 1958; 1960-1963; 3.2
    - A, Undated; 3.2.1 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 1)
      - 1. Abschied von Schwarzwald, Undated
      - 2. Afterthought, Undated
      - 3. Agonizing Reappraisal, Undated
      - 4. Als ich die Feldblumen wiedersah, Undated
      - 5. Alte Damen gehn auf Reisen, Undated
      - 6. Alte Liebe spricht, Undated
      - 7. Alte Pelz, Der, Undated
      - 8. Altes Reunpferd, Undated
      - 9. Ambivalence of Rhyme, Undated
      - 10. American Welfare Case, An, Undated
      - 11. Am Grabe Rainer Maria Rilkes, Undated
      - 12. Amoklaeufer, Der, Undated
      - 13. Angry Man, Undated
      - 14. And Yet a Star!, Undated
      - 15. An einen alternden Dichter, Undated
      - 16. Art and Nature, Undated
      - 17. Arizona Indian Dancing, Undated
      - 18. Arriving at Grand Central, Undated
      - 19. As Told To..., Undated
      - 20. Astronomical Exposure, Undated
      - 21. At the Grave of Rainer Maria Rilke, 1958
      - 22. Aus einer kleinen Fuge der Zeit, Undated
      - 23. Auto Graveyard, Undated
    - B, Undated; 3.2.2 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 2)
      - 1. Ballad of a Wayward Tree, Undated
      - 2. Ballad of the Mistaken Villanelle, Undated
      - 3. Ballad of the Prodigal Father, Undated
      - 4. Because Thou Art, Undated
      - 5. Beginning and End, Undated
      - 6. Between Two Worlds (and two languages); also in German, Undated
      - 7. Bough and the Bird, The, Undated
      - 8. Brandstaette, Undated
      - 9. Bra Troubadours, The, Undated
    - C, Undated; 3.2.3 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 3)
      - 1. Caprice of Associations, Undated
      - 2. Career, Undated
      - 3. Caress, Undated
      - 4. Centaur, 1963
      - 5. Chameleon (pubd. in Deutsche Rundschau, 1:90, Jan. 1964: 69), Undated
      - 6. Clear the Docket, Undated
      - 7. Colt in one Movement, Undated
      - 8. Comfort for Shut-Ins, Undated
      - 9. Commentators, Undated
      - 10. Concluding Statements, Undated
      - 11. Conspiracy of Silence, Undated
      - 12. Convert, The, Undated
    - D, Undated; 3.2.4 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 4)
      - 1. Denn jemand musste es tun..., Undated
      - 2. Desert is an Hourglass, The, Undated
      - 3. Deutung der Worts, Undated
      - 4. Devil's Pact Frustrated, Undated
      - 5. Diary in Verse, Undated
      - 6. Diogenes, Undated
      - 7. Discord in the Home of Pontius Pilatus, Undated
      - 8. Discovery, Undated
      - 9. Don't be a Poor Man, 1961
      - 10. Double Mirror, Undated
      - 11. Dramatic Lingerie (with "Heart Trouble"), Undated
      - 12. Dream of the Empty Hands, 1962
      - 13. Drei Gezeiten, Die, Undated
      - 14. Drei Staedte, Undated
    - E, Undated; 3.2.5 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 5)
      - 1. Ecumenical Man, Undated
      - 2. Electrocardiogram, Undated
      - 3. Elegie an einen alten Pelz, 1962
      - 4. Epigrams, Undated
      - 5. Epitaph for a Failure, Undated
      - 6. Epitaph of an Old Tramp, Undated
      - 7. Erinnern und Vergissen, Undated
      - 8. Everywhere, 1958
    - F, Undated; 3.2.6 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 6)
      - 1. Fallacy of Nostalgia, Undated
      - 2. Fatal Pun, Undated
      - 3. Festival of a Nonconformist, Undated
      - 4. Final Reckoning, Undated
      - 5. First Touch of Nothingness, Undated
      - 6. Fleeting, Undated
      - 7. Foal in one Movement, Undated
      - 8. Fool's Hans Natonek, Papers, Undated
      - 9. Fool's Villanelle, Undated
      - 10. Foreign Poets, Poems for, Undated
      - 11. Forest Fire, 1963
      - 12. Fountain of Youth?, Undated
      - 13. Fremdling in Amerika, 1963
      - 14. Fremdling im Setzersaal, Undated
      - 15. From a Little Fugue of Time, Undated
      - 16. Frustration, Undated
      - 17. Fuerbitte, Undated
      - 18. Funke, Ein, Undated
    - G, Undated; 3.2.7 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 7)
      - 1. Gedichte aus der Ferne, Undated
      - 2. Germany Revisited, Undated
      - 3. Gespenstige Ruckkehr, Undated
      - 4. Giving--Yet Unforgiven?, Undated
      - 5. Great Narrator, The, Undated
    - H, Undated; 3.2.8 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 8)
      - 1. Head and Wall, Undated
      - 2. Heitere Melancholie, Undated
      - 3. Heresy of a Believer, Undated
      - 4. Hourglass Frightens Me, The, Undated
      - 5. Howdunits, The, Undated
    - I, Undated; 3.2.9 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 9)
      - 1. Ich folge dir, Undated
      - 2. Idiom Runs Amuck, An, Undated
      - 3. Im Kurpark von Baden-Baden, 1960
      - 4. In a Key of Blues, Undated
      - 5. In diesen letzten Tagen, Undated
      - 6. In the Same Boat, Undated
      - 7. In zwei Stimmen, Undated
      - 8. I Pray Because You Are, Undated
    - J, Undated; 3.2.10 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 10)
      - 1. Juedischer Kalender, 1962
      - 2. Junk Art on a G-String, Undated
    - K, Undated; 3.2.11 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 11)
      - 1. Kindhertslandschaft, Undated
      - 2. Kleiner Psalter, Undated
      - 3. Kurfurstendamm, 1933-1935
      - 4. Kuss, Der, Undated
    - L, Undated; 3.2.12 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 12)
      - 1. Lament, Undated
      - 2. Last Wisdom, Undated
      - 3. Late Journey, Undated
      - 4. Late Planting, Undated
      - 5. Lazarus, Undated
      - 6. Letter in the dust, A, 1961
      - 7. Letzte Fahrt, 1962 October 31
      - 8. Leukemia, Undated
      - 9. Libelle, Undated
      - 10. Lied eines Taugenichts, Undated
      - 11. Lied inn der Wuste, 1962
      - 12. Lines, Undated
      - 13. Little Biography, Undated
      - 14. Little Psalm, Undated
      - 15. Lone Wolf's Holidays, Undated
      - 16. Lost Tranquillity, Undated
      - 17. Love out of Season, Undated
      - 18. Lust am Wort, Undated
      - 19. Lust of Words, Undated
    - M, Undated; 3.2.13 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 13)
      - 1. Mailed, Undated
      - 2. Mascara, Undated
      - 3. Marginal Notes on Magazines, Undated
      - 4. Meeting So Late, S. Mein Erloeser, Undated
      - 5. Melodische Luftspiegelung, Undated
      - 6. Merry Melancholy, Undated
      - 7. Message, 1962
      - 8. Meteor, Undated
      - 9. Mimosa, 1962
      - 10. Monique's Metamorphosis, Undated
      - 11. Montaigne, Undated
      - 12. Monterey's Cannery Row, Undated
      - 13. Moon Caprice, Undated
      - 14. Mother Passing By, A, 1961
      - 15. More than Quotations, Undated
      - 16. My Prayers Are..., Undated
      - 17. My Savior..., Undated
    - N, Undated; 3.2.14 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 14)
      - 1. Naechtliche Bibliothek, Undated
      - 2. Nichts ist mein, 1961
      - 3. Newcomer's Bewilderment, Undated
      - 4. No Return, Undated
      - 5. Nornen, Die, Undated
      - 6. Not Chosen, Undated
    - O, Undated; 3.2.15 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 15)
      - 1. Obit of a Gossip Columnist, Undated
      - 2. Obscurity, Undated
      - 3. Obsession with a Name, Undated
      - 4. Old Love Speaks, 1960
      - 5. Old Man on a County Fair, Undated
      - 6. Old Tunes, Undated
      - 7. On a G-String, Undated
      - 8. On a String, Undated
      - 9. On Cliches, Undated
      - 10. On Identity, Undated
      - 11. On Rhyme, Undated
      - 12. On the German Word Habseligkeiten, Undated
      - 13. Our Commentators, Undated
      - 14. Outlook, 1962
      - 15. Out-of-date, Undated
      - 16. Out of Waste, Undated
    - P, Undated; 3.2.16 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 16)
      - 1. Palo Verde, Undated
      - 2. Paris Revisited, Undated
      - 3. Paris Statue Revisited, A, Undated
      - 4. Past is a Pasture, Undated
      - 5. Pebbles, Undated
      - 6. Piano Tunes, Undated
      - 7. Pilgrimage in Proxy, Undated
      - 8. Place Called Home, A, Undated
      - 9. Pleasant Journey to You!, Undated
      - 10. Poetry and Prose, Undated
      - 11. Point and Counterpoint of Rhyme, Undated
      - 12. Pond and Puddle, Undated
      - 13. Portrait of a Scoundrel, Undated
      - 14. Portrayal, Undated
      - 15. Portrayals, Undated
      - 16. Prayer's Pitch, Undated
      - 17. Probing a Loss, Undated
      - 18. Probing His Depth (pubd. in Deutsche Rundschau. 1:90, Jan. 1964: 69), Undated
      - 19. Pyre, The, Undated
    - Q, Undated; 3.2.17 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 17)
      - 1. Questions, Undated
    - R, Undated; 3.2.18 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 18)
      - 1. Reim, Undated
      - 2. Recovery in the Arizona Desert, Undated
      - 3. Regret for the Vanished Year, 1960
      - 4. Religious Poems, Undated
      - 5. Remains, 1962
      - 6. Remembrance of a Rainy Night, Undated
      - 7. Report from the Bullfight Circuit, Undated
      - 8. Resignation, Undated
      - 9. Revenant, The, Undated
      - 10. River, Undated
    - S, Undated; 3.2.19 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 19)
      - 1. Same Question, Undated
      - 2. Sancta Simplicitas, Undated
      - 3. Schmetterlingswiese, Die, 1963
      - 4. Scrooge's Carnival, Undated
      - 5. Scruples, Undated
      - 6. Shocking, Undated
      - 7. Shoot, Undated
      - 8. Should It Be Done?, Undated
      - 9. Secret Message, Undated
      - 10. Self-Dramatization, Undated
      - 11. Sex is..., Undated
      - 12. Shortest War in History, The, Undated
      - 13. Simplicity, Undated
      - 14. Sonett vom Scheiterhaufen, Undated
      - 15. Sonnet in two languages (also in German), Undated
      - 16. Sonnet on Cliches, Undated
      - 17. Spark, A, Undated
      - 18. Spat Aber Vergnugt, 1963
      - 19. Spur, Die, Undated
      - 20. Stimme und das Schweigen, Die, Undated
      - 21. Stranger in the Composing Room, A, Undated
      - 22. Summer Lull, Undated
      - 23. Supreme Design, Undated
      - 24. Survival, Undated
      - 25. Survival Space, Undated
      - 26. Surface and Depth, Undated
      - 27. Sweet Nonsense of Words, Undated
      - 28. Swing, The, Undated
    - T, Undated; 3.2.20 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 20)
      - 1. Tell-Tail, Undated
      - 2. Tender Nights, Undated
      - 3. That Extra Storage Space, Undated
      - 4. Thoreau, 1962
      - 5. Three Cities, Undated
      - 6. Tiefes Schauen, Undated
      - 7. Time, Abide!, Undated
      - 8. To a Global Wall-Map, Undated
      - 9. To an Aging Poet, Undated
      - 10. To a Salesman of Positive Thinking, Undated
      - 11. To a Salesman of Pseudo-Christianity, Undated
      - 12. To an Unslanderable Scoundrel, Undated
      - 13. Tod unter Winterapfeln, Undated
      - 14. Tongue a la Mishmash, Undated
      - 15. Too Close for Comfort, Undated
      - 16. Trace, The, Undated
      - 17. Traum von den leeren Handen, 1963
      - 18. Treibholz im Seine-Fluss, Undated
      - 19. Tropical Twilight, Undated
      - 20. Trost der Fremde, Undated
      - 21. Two Drifts, Undated
      - 22. Two Men Called Lazarus, Undated
      - 23. Two-Way Journey, Undated
    - U, Undated; 3.2.21 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 21)
      - 1. Ueberlebenden, Die, Undated
      - 2. Unbekannte Vom Seine-Fluss, Die, Undated
      - 3. Unerfuellte Begierde, Undated
      - 4. Unerfuelltheit, Undated
      - 5. Unfulfilled, Undated
      - 6. Ungewisse Heinkehr, Undated
      - 7. Ungleiche Liebe, Undated
      - 8. Unknown Statue Revisited, Undated
    - V, Undated; 3.2.22 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 22)
      - 1. Verstummten, Die, 1961
      - 2. Vertigo, Undated
      - 3. Vision in the Composing Room, A, Undated
      - 4. Visit to a Blind Friend, Undated
      - 5. Voice and the Silence, The, Undated
      - 6. Vorgefuehl, 1961
    - W, Undated; 3.2.23 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 23)
      - 1. Waldbrand, Undated
      - 2. Wall Street, Undated
      - 3. Was in aller Welt, Undated
      - 4. Waste, Undated
      - 5. Wastrel, Undated
      - 6. Watching a Tiny Coffin, Undated
      - 7. Welfare Case, A, Undated
      - 8. Welle, Die, Undated
      - 9. We Who Survived, Undated
      - 10. Whatever I Got, Undated
      - 11. What in the World..., Undated
      - 12. What is This Thing Called Prayer?, Undated
      - 13. When I Saw Your First Glasses, Undated
      - 14. Wir, die Uberlebenden, 1962
      - 15. Without Reason, Undated
      - 16. Women in the Moon, Undated
      - 17. Word About Self-Pity, A, Undated
      - 18. Words of Comfort, Undated
      - 19. Words to Live By, Undated
      - 20. Workshop Talk, Undated
      - 21. Wound and the Pearl, The (also in German), Undated
    - Y - Z, Undated; 3.2.24 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 24)
      - 1. You Know Those Types, Undated
      - 2. Zartliche Nachte, Undated
      - 3. Zwischen Zwei Welten (also in English), 1963
  - Short Stories, 1924; 1938-1943; 1949; 1958; 1961-1963; 3.3
    - Damals in der Bar Mistral, 1961 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 25)
    - Diary in the Desert, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 26)
    - Dienst am Kunden, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 27)
    - Durst, 1941 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 28)
    - Enkel Entdeckt Seinen Grossvater, Ein, ca. 1943 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 29)
    - Entdeckung, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 30)
    - Everybody is Against It, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 31)
    - Father is a Cop, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 32)
    - Fall Guy of Matrimony, The, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 33)
    - Fisherman, The, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 34)
    - Forgive Me, Mr. Berkowicz, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 35)
    - Gang des Menchen, Der, 1940 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 36)
    - Gastmal mit Lucullus, Das, 1963 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 37)
    - Geschichte eines Gegenubers, ca. 1938-1941 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 38)
    - Gesprache im Zwischenakt, 1924 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 39)
    - Heimker, 1962 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 40)
    - Herr von Goethe Fahrt Lift, ca. 1940 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 41)
    - House of all Nations, A, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 42)
    - How a Fiasco Became a Success, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 43)
    - I Love Those Border Signs, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 44)
    - In Search of Fetching Titles, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 45)
    - Johnny Gourmand, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 46)
    - Joseph Roth, 1949 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 47)
    - Kampf ums Irrenhaus, ca. 1941-1943 (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 48)
    - Key, The, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 49)
    - King Claudius Applauds, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 50)
    - Legende Roth, Die, 1939 July (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 51)
    - Letters to Lawrence, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 52)
    - Letzte Wiener im Manhattan, Der, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 53)
    - Lockvogel, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 54)
    - Looking for the Satirist, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 55)
    - Lonely Man's Lantern, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 56)
    - Lost Voice of the Past, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 57)
    - Magic Ring, The, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 58)
    - Man Who Stole Tomorrow, The, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 59)
    - Me? Minding My Own Business, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 60)
    - Monuments on Madison Square, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 61)
    - Night in Paris, A, Undated (Box 3 (3-Literary Works), Folder 62)